Louisville, KY • Cell: 502-220-8569

#### **Professional Profile**

f1

**Solution-Driven Business Analyst** with TWENTY years of experience using analytical skills to solve "Big Picture" business problems and provide solutions. Strong design, organization, verbal and written communications skills and enjoy working as a team on projects. translating into business solutions.

## **Business Analysis (20+ years)**

- Gathered customer requirements and performed User Acceptance Testing.
- Created Automated system per Customer's business processes.
- Created websites for Customers.
- Created User Manuals and Documented websites.
- Created training materials, taught classes on workflows, company standards and English language skills.
- Communicated remotely with Programmers in the Pentagon and India.

## Data Analysis (20+ years)

- Improved management decisions by creating a dashboard of schedules, driving history and route data.
- Imported and Transformed customer data.
- Created Reports for Customers.
- Designed "web-scraping" techniques to extract website data.
- Created workflows for Customers.

### Savings

- <u>Saved \$3,000</u> on a data conversion projects using my ProSpec tool, a reduction of 75% (MDC).
- Saved \$2,500 by recovering 6 weeks of data from a corrupt insurance file (CDSI).
- Decreased Costs by tracking driver speed, fuel usage, excessive idling and On-Time history (Ryder).
- Improved logistics by reverse-engineering existing System to create a new web-based logistic application (SSB).
- Improved efficiency and accuracy by creating a Smart Search system to find customer records (NSN).
- Improved speed and accuracy of Customer's systems by creating a more modern system (SSB).

## **Skills Summary**

- Access, Excel, Word, Visio, VBA, SQL, T-SQL, ETL, SSMS, SSRS, SSIS, UAT, FTP, KPI, dashboards
- Agile, SDLC, JAD, SCRUM, SPRINT, Waterfall, Basic JavaScript, CSS, HTML 5
- Documentation, Functional Requirements, Use Cases, Test Cases, Test Plans
- Training, Presentations, Visual Studio, FrontPage, InfoPath, SharePoint, Nintex Workflows

ITT Technical Institute

Indiana Wesleyan University

# **Professional Experience**

Associate's Degree, Info. Systems

**Bachelor's Degree, Management** 

Algebra Tutor (Freelance)	(private, 68 hours)	Louisville, KY	02/2020 to 06/2020
Business Analyst (Freelance)	American Airlines, Nat. Supply Network	Louisville, KY	10/2017 to 03/2020
Business Analyst	Ryder Integrated Logistics	Georgetown, KY	02/2015 to 06/2015
Business Analyst	U.S. Department of Defense (SSB)	Lexington, KY	08/2011 to 06/2014
Business Analyst / Contractor	Core Logic	Louisville, KY	12/2010 to 04/2011
Business Analyst (Freelance)	Various Clients	Louisville, KY	04/2010 to 12/2010
Business Analyst	Quilogy	Louisville, KY	07/2008 to 01/2010
Website Designer	Chile Mission	Santiago, Chile	01/2005 to 08/2006
Business Analyst	Master Data Center	Southfield, MI	04/1995 to 10/2004
Business Analyst	Dept of Defense (CDSI)	Indiana / Michigan	12/1991 to 03/1995
Other Experience			
Lucky's Market	Culinary Associate	Louisville, KY	09/2017 to 02/2020
Red Carpet Inn	Front Desk Associate	Louisville, KY	12/2016 to 02/2017
Direct Insurance Marketing Asso	oc. Life Insurance Interviewer	Louisville, KY	08/2016 to 10/2016
Temp Positions	Various Companies	Louisville, KY	08/2006 to 07/2008
Education			

Indianapolis, IN

Indianapolis, IN